Finding Aid for Boyne USA Resorts records, 1935-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  - Various Topics
    - Challenging conditions, Winter 1957 (Box 22)
    - New Year's Eve (?) celebrants dining (Box 22)
    - Skiers on slope listening to instructor (Box 22)
    - Skiers on slope, Hanson Challenge February 1974, 2 photographs; color print (Box 52)
    - Boyne Mountain slopes in wintertime, color print (Box 52)
    - Two skiers in Grand Prix competition, color print (Box 52)
    - WLLZ morning radio crew while broadcasting from Boyne Mountain, color print (Box 52)
      (autographed)
    - Skiers on slopes and in chair lifts 1965, 4 prints black and white (Box 52)
      (photographs by Tom Smart)
  - Promotional photographs
    - Skiers and skiing; also snowmobiling (Box 51)
    - Golfers and golf course holes (Box 51)
    - Facilities in summer (Box 51)
    - Facilities in winter, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Big Sky (Box 51)
    - Ski slope diagram (Box 51)
    - Aerial photographs of property (Box 51)
    - Swimming pool (Box 51)
  - Framed color photographs
    - Big Sky Resort (Object 1)
    - Boyne Highlands (Object 2)
    - Brighton Ski Bowl (Object 3)
    - Boyne Mountain (Object 4)
- Negatives
  The fifth series, Negatives, is organized into loose negatives and binders. The loose negatives are organized alphabetically by topic. The negatives contain images of various Boyne properties, activities, construction, and people.
  - Loose Negatives
    - Anton Engelbert "Toni" Sailer undated (Box 23)
    - Big Sky undated (Box 23)
    - Boyne Mountain 2001 (Box 23)
    - Boyne Mountain Spring Party 2000 (Box 23)
    - Construction at Boyne Mountain circa 1960s (Box 23)
    - Everett Kircher undated (Box 23)
    - Heather Highlands Inn undated (Box 23)
    - Opening of Boyne Mountain Golf Course undated (Box 23)
    - Pro Races 1988 (Box 23)
    - Ross Golf Course undated (Box 23)
    - Maps of Boyne Highlands and Boyne Mountain 1996 (Box 23)
    - Skiing at Boyne Mountain 1961 (Box 23)
    - Snowmobiling at Boyne Mountain undated (Box 23)
    - Snow Melt 1988 (Box 23)
    - Test Drive Advertisement 2001 (Box 23)
    - Young Americans 1987 (Box 23)
    - Zig Bulanda undated (Box 23)
    - Big Sky circa 1970s (Box 23)
  - Binders
    - Bay Harbor Golf 1993-2003 (scattered) and undated (Box 23)
    - Black and White Negatives (Box 23)
    - Boyne USA Events 1994-1999 (scattered) and undated (Box 23)
    - Color Negatives (Box 23)
- Photographic Slides
  Photographic slides, the sixth series, contains color slides of Bay Harbor, Boyne Mountain, Boyne Highlands, Big Sky, Crystal Mountain, and the Gatlinburg Sky Lift. The images date from 1961 to 2005 and document activities, construction, buildings, and events. The first part of the series consists of albums, mostly of summer and winter events, and the second part of the series consists of loose slides organized by resort and topic.
  - Albums of Photographic Slides
    - Ski slide library (Box 24)
    - Snowboard and Pro tour event (Box 24)
    - Boyne Ski Photos (Box 24)
    - Winter events, 4 volumes (Box 25)
    - Winter Events, 3 volumes (Box 26)
    - Summer Events, 4 volumes (Box 27)
    - Golf 2003 Bay Harbor & Heather Highlands (Box 28)
    - Golf Miscellaneous, 2 volumes (Box 28)
    - Golf Slide Library (Box 28)
    - Bay Harbor Golf, 2 volumes (Box 28)
    - Shell Tournament 1998 (Box 29)
    - Monument 1987 (Box 29)
    - The Moor 1987 (Box 29)
    - The Alpine 1987 (Box 29)
    - Heather Highland 1987 (Box 29)
    - Golf Misc. (Box 30)
    - Bar Harbor construction (Box 30)
    - Golf: Super 5 Junior Top C 1994 (Box 30)
    - Boyne Mountain Golf (Box 31)
    - Golf Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - Golf 1986-1987 (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 32)
    - Boyne 1997, 2000 (Box 32)
    - Golf Miscellaneous, 3 volumes (Box 32)
  - Other slides
    - Bay Harbor
      - General, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - The Quarry Golf Course (Box 33)
    - Big Sky
      - General (Box 33)
    - Boyne Mountain
      - Beach House (Box 33)
      - Billy Kidd 1986 (Box 33)
      - Construction (Box 33)
      - Construction of Super Bowl Lift with Helicopter 1984 (Box 33)
      - Winter 2005, 3 folders (Box 33)
      - Golf (Box 33)
      - Monument Golf Course (Box 33)
      - T-Champions 1999 (Box 33)
    - Boyne Highlands
      - General (Box 33)
      - Construction 1963-1966, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Art Hills Golf Course (Box 33)
      - Pro-Racing (Box 33)
      - Convention Center (Box 33)
      - Donald Ross Memorial Golf Course 1986 (Box 33)
      - Golf 1983, undated (Box 33)
      - Celebrity Tour (Box 33)
      - PGA 1999 (Box 33)
      - Highlands Inn (Box 33)
      - Heather Highlands Condos (Box 33)
      - Heather Golf Course Clubhouse (Box 33)
    - Crystal Mountain
      - General 1995 (Box 33)
    - Gatlinburg Sky Lift
      - Sky Lift 2000 (Box 33)
      - Chairlift Rides 2001 (Box 33)
    - General
      - BNGA (Box 34)
      - Boyne Employees and Friends (Box 34)
      - Byron Nelson and Jim Flick 1990 (Box 34)
      - Children 1986-1987, undated (Box 34)
      - Condominiums 1978, 1985-1986, undated (Box 34)
      - Events 1981-1989 (scattered) (Box 34)
      - Everett Kircher 1975 (Box 34)
      - Exterior and Aerial Shots of Boyne Mountain and Boyne Highlands 1986 (Box 34)
      - Fire undated (Box 34)
      - Golf 1975-1999 (scattered) and undated, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Golf Writers 1983, 1989 (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous 1971-2005 (scattered) and undated, 9 folders (Box 34)
      - Mt. Newcomb Golf 1983 (Box 34)
      - Pro-Races undated (Box 34)
      - Skiing 1961-2005 (scattered) and undated, 4 folders (Box 35)
      - Ski School 2002 (Box 35)
      - Snowmaking 1985-1987 (Box 35)
      - Tennis 1987 (Box 35)
      - Winter 2004-2005 (Box 35)
      - Women 1986-1987 (Box 35)
  - Color Transparencies, 2.25 inches x 2.25 inches
    - Boyne Highlands
      - Bartley House 1969 (Box 35)
      - First Boyne National Golf Academy 1969 (Box 35)
    - Boyne Mountain
      - Cessna District Meeting 1968 (Box 35)
    - General
      - Miscellaneous 1963-1971, undated (Box 35)
- Videotapes
  The seventh series, Videotapes, contains VHS, U-Matic, Beta, and open reel videotapes of Boyne USA events, interviews, and advertising. The tapes date back to the early 1980s and continue to 2003.
  - Commercially produced VHS cassettes
    - 1992
      - Boyne USA Resorts
        - Super Five
          - June 7-12, 1992 (Box 36)
          - June 21-26, 1992 (Box 36)
          - June 27-July 3, 1992 (Box 36)
        - Tournament of Champions
          - July 19-22, 1992 (Box 36)
        - Super Five
          - July 26-31, 1992 (Box 36)
          - August 2-7, 1992 (Box 36)
          - August 9-14, 1992 (Box 36)
          - August 23-28, 1992 (Box 36)
    - 1994
      - Michigan Challenge Ski Race January 31, 1994 (Box 36)
    - 1995
      - Winter Wonderland, Michigan's Golden Age of Skiing (Box 36)
      - Boyne Highland Downhill March 1995 (Box 36)
      - Bay Harbor Golf Development, ESPN September 1995 (Box 36)
    - 1997
      - Sponsorship Verification, Miss Michigan USA/Teen USA (Box 36)
      - Boyne USA Golf Classic June 8-9, 1997 (Box 36)
    - 1998
      - Sponsorship Verification, Miss Michigan USA/Teen USA (Box 36)
      - GM Card, Head for the Hills (Box 37)
      - Boyne USA Resorts (Box 37)
      - Boyne USA Resorts July 1998 (Box 37)
    - 1999
      - Boyne USA Ski School & Skiing 1999-2000 (Box 37)
    - 2000
      - Alpine Rapture, Compilation Ski Movie Demo (Box 37)
      - Events (Box 37)
      - Mountain Grand Lodge & Spa, Groundbreaking September 23, 2000 (Box 37)
    - 2001
      - Everett Kircher Interview with Jim Neff July 15, 2001 (Box 37)
    - 2002
      - Boyne Mtn/Highlands (Box 37)
    - 2003
      - Boyne USA Resorts (Box 37)
      - Everett Kircher, A Video Tribute (Box 37)
    - Undated
      - Bay Harbor, Beauty Shots (Box 37)
      - Bay Harbor, Interview (Box 37)
      - Bay Harbor, the Inn at, the Crown Jewel of Midwest Resorts (Box 37)
      - Bay Harbor: The Place, the Feeling (Box 37)
      - Boyne Country Video (Box 37)
      - Boyne Highlands Conference Facilities (Box 38)
      - Boyne Mountain & Boyne Highlands (Box 38)
      - Boyne USA Resorts, a Look at (Box 38)
      - Boyne USA Resorts, Super Five Golf (2 different years) (Box 38)
      - HBO Real Sports, with Bryant Gumbel, Segment Featuring Jimmie Huega Center (Box 38)
      - Kircher Wedding (Box 38)
      - Lehman vs. Mickleson (Box 38)
      - Mountain Grand Lodge and Spa, Groundbreaking Activities and Historic Footage with Everett Kircher, Stein Eriksen, Othmar Schneider, Warren Miller & Bill Flemming (Box 38)
  - Other VHS Videotapes
    - Golf
      - 1985-1992, 7 audiocassettes (Box 38)
      - 1992-1994, 21 audiocassettes (Box 39)
      - 1994-1998, 10 audiocassettes (Box 40)
    - Skiing
      - 1986-1993, 10 audiocassettes (Box 40)
      - 1993-1994, 18 audiocassettes (Box 41)
      - 1994-1997, undated, 8 audiocassettes (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1986
        - John & Sarah Kircher Wedding, 2 audiocassettes (Box 42)
      - 1993 Zoo-De-Mackinac (Box 42)
      - 1994 Mountain Biking (Box 42)
      - 1995
        - ESPN, APSS Show #4 (Box 42)
        - ESPN MT Snowboard Event (Box 42)
  - U-Matic tapes
    - 1981-1990, 10 audiocassettes (Box 43)
    - 1990-1993, undated, 10 audiocassettes (Box 44)
    - Undated, 9 audiocassettes (Box 45)
      (include 3 tapes of Kircher Wedding)
  - Beta
    - 2002
      - Everett Kircher Historical B-Roll, Pierpont Video Productions, Boyne USA Resorts January 16, 2002 (Box 45)
  - Open reel videotapes
    - Boyne Mountain skiing clip 1972 ABC Color Videotape, 2 in. (Reel 1)
- Motion pictures
  Motion Pictures, the eighth series, documents skiing, ski racing, and the promotional activities of Boyne USA in the 1950s, 1960s, and 1970s. The series contains three 8mm film cartridges and 25 16mm films.
  - 8 mm film cartridges
    - Big Sky Summer (Box 46)
    - Boyne USA; Ski the Summer, 13 min; 2 copies (Box 46)
    - RCI: Time-sharing & Exchange (Box 46)
  - 16 mm reels
    - A Ski Week, Franz Trauner
      (Film No. 21)
    - Big Sky Architect 1st December 1974 cartoon
      (Film No. 7)
    - Black and White Cartoon
      (Film No. 8)
    - Boyne Highlands
      (Film No. 24)
    - Boyne Mountain
      (Film No. 19)
    - Boyne Mountain Lift Construction
      (Film No. 9)
    - Boyne Mountain Lodge, Boyne Falls, Michigan
      (Film No. 10)
    - Boyne Mountain Lodge, Winter Sports in West Michigan, sound
      (Film No. 4)
    - Fun and pictures in the Southern Highlands
      (Film No. 23)
    - Gonna Build a Mountain
      (Film No. 1)
    - Jimmie Huega (Olympic medalist) film 1986
      (Film No. 3)
    - Othmar Schneider demonstrating Austrian skiing technique
      (Film No. 2)
    - Ski the Sky
      (Film No. 5)
    - Ski Wild Mountain
      (Film No. 20)
    - Skiing at the Mountain, late 1950s or 1964
      (Film No. 6)
    - Steamboat's a comin'
      (Film No. 11)
    - Stein Turned On (Larson Industries), sound; color
      (Film No. 22)
    - Wedelyn ski technique (produced by the Henke Ski Boot Company)
      (Film No. 18)
    - When the Bell Says Boyne 1975
      (5 copies)
      (Film Nos. 12-15)
    - When the Bell Says Boyne, Reel A 1975
      (Film No. 16)
    - When the Bell Says Boyne, Reel B 1975
      (Film No. 17)
    - Wild World of Sports K 2 Cup Races, Boyne Mountain February 1972
      (Film No. 25)
- Sound Recordings
  The ninth series, Sound Recordings, primarily documents Boyne's radio presence in the form of interviews, advertisements, and concerts. The recordings are on eight 3 inch reels and 27 cassette tapes.
  - 3 in. reels
    - "12 Hour Ticket" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 1)
    - "Big Sky" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 2)
    - "Black Diamond Rush, Generic" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 3)
    - "Celebrity Players Tour" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 4)
    - "Gatlinburg Sky Lift" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 5)
    - "Hawaiian Tropic" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 6)
    - "Ride the Gatlinburg Sky Lift" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 7)
    - "Search-not" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 8)
  - Cassette Tapes
    - "Bamboo Gang" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 9)
    - "Boyne Concert Series," November 28, 1989 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 10)
    - "Boyne Highlands/Travel Michigan," Greater Cleveland Golf Show (Box 47)
      (tape no. 11)
    - "Boyne Mountain Concert Series," November 21, 1989 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 12)
    - "Boyne Mountain Giveaway," Jonathan Brandmeier Show (Box 47)
      (tape no. 13)
    - "Boyne Mountain Promo," 1985-1986 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 14)
    - "Boyne Mountain/Tropic-Wild," January 27, 1990 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 15)
    - "Boyne Night Skiing" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 16)
    - "Boyne USA" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 17)
    - "Boyne USA Concert-Gen" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 18)
    - "Boyne Winner" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 19)
    - Compositions of Bert Fischer (cassette tape) (Box 47)
      (tape no. 20)
    - "Cross Country Ski" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 21)
    - "D. A. R. E. Tournament," 1991 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 22)
    - "Employment" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 23)
    - "Golf/Lodging" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 24)
    - "Golf Zippo" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 25)
    - "Jimmie Huega Express," 1990 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 26)
    - JJ and Dick Bruiser, Boyne Mountain, WLLZ (Box 47)
      (tape nos. 27-28)
    - "Mr. Kircher" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 29)
    - "P. A. R. Golf," May 28, 1985 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 30)
    - "Ski It To Believe It" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 31)
    - "Sixty Miles Per Hour" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 32)
    - Steve King, Huega Express January 10, 1991 (Box 47)
      (tape no. 33)
    - "Tension" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 34)
    - WJR Interview, "P.A.R Golf" (Box 47)
      (tape no. 35)
- Art work
  The tenth series, Artwork, consists of drawing and paintings portraying ski activities.
  - Paintings and other drawings of skiers and ski slopes (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 53)
- Architectural concept and promotional boards
  Architectural concept and promotional boards, the eleventh series, contains plans for buildings and grounds at Boyne Mountain and Boyne Highlands and large promotional images for Boyne USA.
  - Illustrative "Village Center Plan Boyne Mountain, 24"x17" on foam board (Map-case 1)
  - Preliminary Opportunities Concept Boyne Mountain, 24"x16 3/4" on foam board (Map-case 1)
  - Mountain Base Condominium Plan Boyne Highlands, 17"x24" on foam board (Map-case 1)
  - The Inn at Bay Harbor, Phase II Conceptual Site Plan 1999, 24"x36" on foam board (Map-case 1)
  - "Village Center Detail Boyne Mountain 2000, 42 3/8"x29 3/4" on foam board (Map-case 1)
  - Artists conception of various facilities, 5 items; most 13x24" on masonite (Map-case 2)
  - Promotional photos of Boyne USA facilities, 5 items; most 16x24" (Map-case 2)
  - Promotional posters (Map-case 3)
    (include Boyne Country Daily Ski Report, two variations)
  - Promotional photographs (Map-case 3)
  - Bay Harbor Master Site Plan, 13x60" (Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous office records
  Miscellaneous Office Records, the twelfth series consists of two oversized volumes documenting alcohol inventory and conference bookings.
  - Storeroom inventory of alcohol: beer, wine, liquor 1981-1987, 3 volumes
    - Storeroom inventory of alcohol: beer, wine, liquor 1981-1987 (Volume 12)
    - Storeroom inventory of alcohol: beer, wine, liquor 1981-1987 (Volume 13)
    - Storeroom inventory of alcohol: beer, wine, liquor 1981-1987 (Volume 14)
  - Calendar of conference bookings 1971-1972, 4 columnar pads (Volume 15)
- Scrapbooks and clippings
  The thirteenth series, Scrapbooks and Clippings, contains scrapbooks of news releases and several folders of news clippings related to Boyne USA provided by a news clipping service.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1948-1953 1969 (Volume 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Volume 2)
    - 1961 (Volume 3)
    - 1962-1963 (Volume 4)
    - 1961-1963 (Volume 19)
    - General news releases 1964-1967 (Volume 5)
    - Skiing news releases 1968-1969 (Volume 6)
    - Skiing news stories 1968-1969 (Volume 7)
    - Golf news releases 1968-1969 (Volume 8)
    - Convention news releases 1968-1969 (Volume 9)
    - General news releases January 1970-January 1973 (Volume 10)
    - Boyne Tournament of Champions 1992-1993 (Volume 11)
  - Clippings from news clipping service
    - 1977-1978 (Box 48)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 49)
    - 1960s-2000s (Box 50)
      (unprocessed)
- Miscellaneous
  Miscellaneous, the fourteenth and final series, consists of oversize certificates, commemorative materials, and informational placards related to Boyne USA resorts, events, and history.
  - Certificates, commemorative materials, informational placards, etc. (Box 54)